Guide to the Yale Sailing Associates Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Sailing Associates recprds
1958-1993
RU 134
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5
(9 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, minutes of meetings, reports, financial statements, association notices, bulletins, and other papers documenting the activities of the Yale Sailing Associates.
Yale Sailing Associates
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies, and organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale Sailing Associates is the alumni organization of the Yale Corinthian Yacht Club.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, minutes of meetings, reports, financial statements, association notices, bulletins, and other papers documenting the activities of the Yale Sailing Associates.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Boats and boating; Sailing; Yachting -- Societies, etc.; Yale Sailing Associates; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University -- Societies, etc.; Yale University. Yale Corinthian Yacht Club
- Records, circa 1963-1974; Accession 19ND-A-008
  - Yale Sailing associates
    - Annual solicitations and thank you letters, 1965-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Thank you from Alexandra Kietor, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1A)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - New Member drive, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Executive Committee Records, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - gifts, 1964-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Capital drive for New Sailing Center, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Dupont Resolution, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Marine Historical Association, Inc., 1963 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Yacht "Xanadu", 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Fleet Purchase, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - New Fleet "Named" Boats, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Purchase of Boats and Equipment, 1966-1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - YSA Foundation Proposal, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Yale Sailing Center
    - Yale Sailing Center, 1964-1973 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Historical and Archival (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Diagrams of Proposed Sailing Center (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Yale Corinthian Yacht Club
    - YCYC Membership, 1964-1973 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - YCYC Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - File Cards YCYC, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - YCYC "Junior Program", 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - YCYC-Sale of Boats, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Regatta Reports, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - U.S. International Collegiate Sailing Team, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Fales Committee, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Yale Faculty Yacht Club
    - Yale Faculty Yact Club (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Publications and Clippings
    - Newsletters, 1964-1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Booklets, Pamphlets, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Sailing instruction, printed matter (Box 4, Folder 32A)
    - Clippings, 1964-1971 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Financial Statements
    - Gift Memoranda of YSA, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Remittance Slips-YSA, 1969-1974 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Requisitions and Invoices, 1967-1973 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Financial Statements of YSA Gifts, 1965-1972 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Photographs and Miscellany
    - Photographs (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Photographs (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Letterhead and Map Markers (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - YSA Belt Insignia (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Records, 1958-1968; Accession 1987-A-029
  - Correspondence, minutes of meetings, and lists pertaining to the raising of funds for the purchase of sailboats and for the Short Beach facility, 1958-1968 (Box 1)
- Administrative records, 1967-1993; Accession 1994-A-066
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2028.
  - Yale Corinthian Yacht Club organization and Operational Manual, 1992 November (Box 1)
  - YSA List of Old Blue, 1967-1974 (Box 1)
  - Brush Painting Sold to Benefit YSA (Box 1)
  - YSA Background Information Sheets (Box 1)
  - YSA Yale Corinthian Yacht Club Constitution, 1970 Revision (Box 1)
  - YSA America's Cup (Box 1)
  - America's Cup Brief (Box 1)
  - YSA General Correspondence (Box 1)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 1)
    - 1991-1992 (Box 1)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 1)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 1)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 1)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 1)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 1)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 1)
    - 1978-1981 (Box 1)
    - 1974-1978 (Box 1)
  - YSA 32610 Monthly Statements, -1971 (Box 1)
  - YSA 65510 Monthly Statements (Box 2)
    - 1985-1991 (Box 2)
    - 1991-1993 (Box 2)
  - YSA Membership Lists (Box 2)
  - YSA Printing (Box 2)
  - Noyes Fellows Honoraria (Box 2)
  - YSA 11250 Noyes Statements (Box 2)
    - 1987-1991 (Box 2)
    - 1991-1993 (Box 2)
  - YSA Noyes Fund (Box 2)
  - YSA Bills, Receipts, etc. (Box 2)
  - YSA Dunning Letter from Dick Vietor
    - 1992 (Box 2)
    - 1991 (Box 2)
  - YSA Annual Meeting (Box 2)
    - 1992
    - 1991 (Box 2)
    - 1990 (Box 2)
    - 1989 (Box 2)
  - YSA Annual Meetings, Minutes, and Treasurer's Reports (Box 2)
  - YSA Request for Contributions (December) (Box 2)
  - Russian Trips (Moscow) (Box 2)
  - Donations, 1988-1993 (Box 2)
  - Members and Contributors (Box 2)
  - Accounting Records, 1985-1993 (Box 2)
- Yale Sailing Asssociates Treasurer's correspondence and the Association's Newsletter, 1974-1993; Accession 1994-A-112
  Restricted until January 1, 2028
  - Treasurer's correspondence (Box 1)
  - Newsletter (Box 1)